Now I'm going to demonstrate how to cut out only a small part of an image.
As always the important part is choosing the right image.
You can do this with any photo you can stick out ends of the object like table corners hands legs handsbranches and so on any object that has a prominent tipfirst step in this process to define the container of the image the frame in which it sets because you'resticking something out of that frame.
If you're going to use the photo as a full background photo then edges off your frame are actually notvisible.
You can't stick anything out.
I'm going to work on this image in this tutorial I have linked the same image so you can follow along.
We can easily stake out that year of the dog.
That means our frame has to have a top border.
If you stretches from top to bottom of the screen then this image won't work at all.
But if I use a frame like a circle for example then I can stick that year out without a problem.
So let's frame the photo firstjust like we're doing figure we're going to create a mask.
We're going to use the same masking tool as we did previously in the cut out method but this time insteadof selecting the dog from the background we're going to select a circle.
Part of that dog in the marquee tool right click on it and select the elliptical market.
All this is in other words select or I don't even know what market means now by dragging select theface of the dog hold shift while you do this so you can draw a perfect circle to get a better handleyou can press on spacebar to move this election around.
You don't need to get this perfectly right now.
We can always resize and reposition the image of the dog later as we did last time.
Click Select and mask up here.
You're already familiar with this mask Ed but we're not going to add a here or anything actually becausewe need a perfect circle mask.
So right away go to output options and select new layer with layer mask like we did last time.
Third now we have the same arrangement as in the cut out methodif you need to reposition or re scale the image inside we can do that similarly like we do in figureselect the move tool first.
By default Mass Group is locked so you can move the image separately it's moving an entire group tomove just the image or just the mass click on this link icon here.
It will unlike the image from the mask and now you can move them separately by selecting either theimage or the mask from the latest listyou'll notice that mask and Photoshop is a defined space as it was defined originally.
That's why we have this extra bits showing here.
If you end up with this extra bits after moving your image around you can just crop this out with acrop top.
By the way Photoshop has this very handy tool called History panel.
Instead of undoing on an eye you can go directly to the stamp that you want to undo.
I love this historic tool and Photoshop makes undoing much easier.
OK so repositioning image inside is easy.
Just drag the image around but to re scale the image select the image layer and then go to edit andfree transform.
Now you can grab the handles and resize it as you wish.
Hold Shift to lock the ratio here in my hand.
I'm imagining what parts I'm going to stick out so I can position the image properlynow that we have prepared our main frame in which our image sets.
We can now stick that year out of it to do this.
We're going to basically cut out a piece of the dogs here as a separate layer and place it on top ofthis existing layer.
So right click on this mass group and duplicate the layernow right click on the mask itself not the entire layer but just the mask and click delete layer masknow we have the full image on top of it.
If we cut out a chunk of the year from this full image and remove the rest we will get the exact stickout.
In fact we want to do so we do the usual cut out method just like we did in the previous lesson.
Grab a quick selection toolset the right brush from the options from here.
Make sure you have selected the brush with the plus sign not the minus set the hardness to 100 percentand set the right size so you can select that year easilyturn they'll pass it down to see the edge of the frame and select accordinglyyou can select more of the image on the bottom because it's not going to do us harm.
It's just going to be sitting on top of the existing photo anyways that looks good.
Now click select and mask.
We are seeing both of the layers here.
Our frame layer and just that your layer.
Let's change the background to white for now so we can refine the edge of that yearremember how to refine that just select the refined H2 and go over the edges.
So it adds in any missing hair or any other missing pixels as I mentioned before with this tool we aretelling Photoshop to look beyond our selection and detect any missing pixels.
You don't have to refine the base of the year it will merge perfectly with the background image.
Now go to output settings and select new layer with layer mask and hit.
OK there.
That's our ear sticking out let's put a white background on this so we can see the results better.
Create new layerand click the new feel I can hear.
Select solid color and choose whitenow drag that layer below everythingif you're going to use a different color in your actual designs.
You can double click on the feel and change the color so you can visualize this right here in Photoshopbefore you export the final result.
For example when I put this on a dark color we can notice that there is some extra layer behind theear.
Too bad I didn't check this one refining the selection but we can still do some work on this.
Even after the mask has been applied the mask is still editable.
If we zoom in on the mask layer you'll see we have black and white parts the white parts are visiblepart of the mask and black parts are hidden part.
That's why the white part has a shape of the ear.
If we paint white on this mask we will show more of the image.
Let me demonstrateif I select a regular rational and draw on it with white paint.
It's going to show more of the imageand if I draw with a black paint on it it will hide whatever is already visibleto switch between white and black brush.
Click on this arrow icon on top of this black and white boxes.
Whatever is on top is the current color of the brush.
There is also a shortcut.
You can hit X on your keyboard and then it will switch between the two.
Okay now we can remove the extra glare from behind the ear.
I'm going to adjust the brush to make it smooth and feathery so I don't create any hard edges.
In this case I'm going to decrease the hardness completely and even decrease the passage to 50 percent.
This way I will brush over the parts and in a smooth and controlled manner.
And that's a better result.
It might not be ideal on a black background but works quite well.
Best to refine this during the masking face.
And don't forget to check the view on the black background.
If you plan on using it on dark backgroundsthe last step is to export the image we're going to export in PSG with a transparent background.
That way you have more freedom to choose background directly.
In fact my during actual design process height the background crop out any extra space.
And under File Export.
Click quick export as PNCand there you have it.
This can be now important inside FEMA and use on different backgrounds.